RESUME

HENRY PAUL SURESH.Y

Contact: 63825-88185.

Mail Id: henrysrsh79@gmail.com

Profile Summary:

An organized and creative professional with proven Marketing and Sales skills and a desire to learn more. Possess 14+ years of experience working for a diverse group of Organization. Right now I am looking for a challenging position in the field of Business development where I can utilize my experience of working in a highly competitive industries and to contribute my management / Leadership and interpersonal skills to set to increase companies Profitability, where I can grow along with the organization.

Career Skills:

- Product Brand Promotion New product launching
- Ability to meet deadlines.
- Multi tasking
- > Time Management
- ➤ Active learning
- Coordination

Strengths:

- Effective collaboration with management to determine needs and discuss progression
- Strong organizational skills.
- ➤ Ready to Embrace new challenges and contribute to the organizations overall success.
- Team Work and leadership.
- > Employee relations and mediations.
- Customer service and relationship management
- Sincerity towards job and punctuality

Work Experience Details:

- ➤ Worked as A Marketing Executive for **Carvez Web Solutions** January 2005 to July 2006.
- ➤ Worked as a Sales Executive in **Reliance Communication** Coimbatore for a period of one year from August 2006 to June 2007.
- ➤ NITCO TILES Ltd as Sr. Executive Trade Marketing Brand Promoter(ROTN) from July 2007 to November 2011.

Nature of work as Sr Ex Trade Marketing Executive. (BRAND PROMOTION)

- All Brand promotional Activity. (Merchandising)
- New Product launches and product training
- In shop branding through registered vendor for dealers and company show rooms.
- Conducting Architect and builders meet. (Sales support).
- Designing for building sector exhibition.
- Maintain entire showrooms of the company all over up country(ROTN)
- Company owned show room expansion (LEE STUDIO)
- Half company operated and half dealer operated(LEE STUDIO EXPRESS)
- Payments for vendor (Raising purchase order)
- Competition tracking and market update and sales support.
- Monitoring and managing allocated budgets.
- Co-ordinations & reporting with HO in weekly & monthly reports.
- Inshop signage Display maintenance.
- Educate about the product to the dealer end sales persons.
- Conducting Architect and builders meet.
- ➤ Worked for I Greens Marketing Solutions (December 2011 to October 2015).
- ➤ Worked for **SOMANY** as **Sr. Executive Trade Marketing Brand Promoter**(ROTN) (November 2015 to May 2018).
- ➤ Self Employed (Own Business) (June 2018 to September 2020).
- ➤ Currently Working for MERINO LAMINATES as Sr. Ececutive Sales support. (From January 2021 till date).
 - Handling all the products of **Merino Laminates** such as **Decorative**Laminates, HPL(Wall cladding) sheets ,HANEX(Korean tops),Prelam Boards
 Vinyl Flooring, Restroom Cubical in showroom Sales and Marketing.
 - Maximize merchandising efforts by using effective displays controlling signage, sales floor or showroom arrangement to ensure that they are attractive and welcoming.
 - Drive the administrative and support functions in the showroom, including management of facilities, supplies, schedules, daily, weekly and monthly showroom reporting.
 - Build effective relationships with Architects ,Interior Designers ,OEMs and Dealers to support the sales.
 - Coordinate with the brand manager for the launching of new brands , allocating Space in the showroom for the brand display.
 - Ability to identify the right product for the client, based on needs/wants.

- The ability to maintain positive relationships with team members, and customers.
- Ability to communicate at all levels across Market.

Education Background:

- Commerce graduate from Pioneer College of Arts and Science in the year June 2004 (M.Com)
- ➤ Commerce graduate from Pioneer College of Arts and Science in the year April 2002 (B.Com)

Computer proficiency:

➤ Diploma in Computer Applications, Internet and Web Technology.

Trainings:

- One month training from Department of Co-operative Milk Societies, Ooty.
- ➤ Two months training from Departments of Hindustan Photo Films, Ooty.

Personal Details:

Name : Y. Henry Paul Suresh

DOB : 26-10-1979

Languages Known : Tamil, English, Hindi, and Malayalam.

Address : W68,FF1,shree Dharsan Avenue Kovaipudur,

Coimbatore 641042

I believe my resume gives the complete information about my personal and technical abilities.

I am looking forward for a better opportunity to prove my skills and knowledge.

Yours Sincerely,

Y.HENRY PAUL SURESH